Guide to the Clyde Brion Davis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1909-1960; Series II; 4.8; (13 boxes)
  - Short Stories and Essays
    - "Spring Grin," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 301)
    - "Star Driver," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 302)
    - "Static Ridge," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 17, Folder 303)
    - "Svengali on the Corner," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 304)
    - "The Swindle Sheet," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 305)
    - "Tamales," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 17, Folder 306)
    - "Teddies," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 307)
    - "Telepathy," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 308)
    - "That Kind of Money," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 17, Folder 309)
    - "The Third Kind," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 310)
    - "Through the Looking Glass," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 311)
    - "Tiddlywink Standard," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 312)
    - "Tips," printed version, 1946 September (Box 17, Folder 313)
    - "To Huitzil, the Left-Handed," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 314)
    - "Tom Mack," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 315)
    - "Torture," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 316)
      Includes undated letter from Tevis Miller and criticism from Carhart and Philip Ketchum
    - "Town Hero," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 17, Folder 317)
    - "Twisted Virtues," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 318)
    - "Vernal Metamorphosis," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 319)
    - "Violets and Firehorses," drafts, typescript, 1949, undated (Box 17, Folder 320)
      Includes letter from Curtis Brown Ltd. dated 6 October 1949
    - "White Cartridge," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 321)
    - "Witch Doctor," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 322)
    - "Words to Live By," drafts, typescript, 1948, undated (Box 17, Folder 323)
    - "Wooden Legs," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 324)
    - "Wormy," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 325)
    - "The Yellow Streak," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 17, Folder 326)
    - "You Never Can Tell," draft, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 327)
    - Untitled, drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 328)
    - Untitled fragments, drafts, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 329)
  - Journalism
    Subseries arranged alphabetically by title of newspaper
    - The Buffalo Times
      - Drafts, undated (Box 18, Folder 330)
      - Printed versions, 1933-1936 (Box 18, Folder 331)
    - Kansas City Star
      - Notes, 1909-1911 (Box 18, Folder 332)
      - Printed versions, 1913
    - PM
      - Printed versions, 1941
    - Radio News
      - Drafts and background material, 1940-1947, undated (Box 18, Folder 333)
    - The Stars and Stripes
      - Printed version, 1919 June13
    - The Trojan Journal
      - Printed versions, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 334)
  - Other Writings
    - Poetry, undated (Box 19, Folder 335)
    - Playscripts
      - "Box Cars," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 19, Folder 336-337)
      - "God-Maker Smith" ("Justice Comes Home"), draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 19, Folder 338)
    - Screenplays
      - "Midnight Bell," draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 19, Folder 339)
      - "Open Hearth," draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 19, Folder 340)
      - "The Royal O'Grady," draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 19, Folder 341)
      - "That Kind of Money," draft, typescript, 1950, undated (Box 19, Folder 342)
        Includes letter from Twentieth-Century Fox Film Corporation dated 1 December 1950
  - Writings of Others
    - Davis, Jeff, "Teapots of Morpheus," draft, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 343)
    - Gill, Burt, "The Incomparable Country Editor," draft, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 344)
    - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, "Adventures in Diet" and "The Problem of Meighen Island," printed versions, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 345)
    - Unidentified, "Betalt!," printed version, Dutch translation, 30 December 1938
    - Unidentified, "Stephen Vincent Benét," printed version, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 346)
- Personal Papers, 1854, 1907-1967; Series III; 18
  The series is organized into two subseries: Financial/Legal Records and Other Papers.
  The series contains financial and legal records such as Davis's taxes, royalty statements, and will as well as other papers.
  - Financial and Legal Records
    - Royalties, 1938-1967 (Box 20, Folder 347-354)
    - Tax records, 1942-1962 (Box 20, Folder 355-358)
    - Will, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 359)
  - Other Papers
    - Cartoon of Davis by R. Osborn, watercolour and crayon, undated
    - Drawing by M.W.D. (Martha Wirt Davis), undated (Box 20, Folder 360)
    - Script for marriage ceremonies, 1948-1952, undated (Box 20, Folder 361)
    - Gleason's Pictorial, 1854
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1941-1961 (Box 20, Folder 362)
    - Souvenir of Elks State Convention, June 1907 (Box 20, Folder 363)
    - Wally: His Cartoons of the A.E.F., 1919
      Publication of cartoons of the American Expeditionary Forces
- Martha Wirt Davis Papers, 1936-1945; Series IV; 4
  The series is organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Writings. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and writings are kept in their original arrangement as pasted onto loose scrapbook pages.
  The series documents Martha Wirt Davis's writing career betweeen 1936 and 1945 while she was living in New York and Connecticut and contains correspondence with magazine editors as well as printed versions of published articles.
  - Correspondence
    - General A-Z, 1940-1945 (Box 20, Folder 364)
    - Davis, Clyde Brion, 1940 August (Box 20, Folder 365)
    - Hillman Periodicals, 1941-1945 (Box 20, Folder 366)
    - Romantic Story, 1941-1943 (Box 20, Folder 367)
  - Writings
    - Printed versions, 1936-1937, undated
- Oversize, 5.01; (3 boxes)
  - The Anointed reviews (Series II), 1937, 1946, undated (Box 21, Folder 368)
  - Nebraska Coast and Northend Wildcats clippings (Series II), 1939-1941 (Box 21, Folder 369)
  - The Buffalo Times printed versions (Series II), 1933-1936 (Box 21, Folder 370-373)
  - Kansas City Star printed versions (Series II), 1913 (Box 22, Folder 374)
  - PM printed versions (Series II), 1941 (Box 22, Folder 375-376)
  - The Stars and Stripes printed versions (Series II), 13 June 1919 (Box 22, Folder 377)
  - "Betalt!," printed version, Dutch translation (Series II), 30 December 1938 (Box 23, Folder 378)
  - Cartoon of Davis by R. Osborn, watercolour and crayon (Series III), undated (Box 23, Folder 379)
  - Gleason's Pictorial clipping (Series III), 1854 (Box 23, Folder 380)
  - Wally: His Cartoons of the A.E.F. (Series III), 1919 (Box 23, Folder 381)
  - Printed versions (Series IV), 1936-1937, undated (Box 23, Folder 382)